Chanson Eric Finney

Email: ericfinney1@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/eric-finney-368b1a6/

Phone: (703) 728-8798 cell GitHub: https://github.com/lyAmGroot

Clearance: Top Secret

GOAL

I am looking for a position as a Front End or Full Stack Developer.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS, TOOLS, AND TECHNOLOGIES:

Programming Languages: JavaScript HTML, CSS, SQL

Frameworks/Platforms: Angular, Bootstrap, Firebase, GitHub, JQuery

Software/COTS: Sybase PowerBuilder, SharePoint 2010 and 2013, Project Server 2013

Operating Systems: Windows (22yrs)

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

I am a professional working as an application developer since 1996 for the United States Army and the Environmental Protection Agency. I have an established track record of being a low maintenance, collaborative team member delivering excellent results. I have been working with SharePoint since 2013 and am currently functioning as a SharePoint site collection administrator. Prior to my SharePoint work I was a PowerBuilder developer.

EXPERIENCE DETAILS

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc.

8/2018 - Present

Fort Belvoir, VA

- SharePoint site collection support working as the Site Collection Administrator for ECMCS, serving over 700 site collections.
- Some technical work updating JavaScript, mostly administrative support supporting mission of maintenance processes and client reporting.

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc.

2/2015 - 6/2018

Fort Belvoir, VA

- SharePoint portal support working as the Site Collection Administrator for the CIO/G-6. Maintained three
 production and three development site collections.
- Created site templates and list templates.
- Created/maintain master pages.
- Created site columns and site content types.
- Created workflows using Nintex (2010/2013) and SharePoint Designer (2010/2013).
- Provided end user training and support.
- Hosted SharePoint site owner meetings to discuss issues, respond to questions, and provide guidance.
- Redesigned sites to take advantage of web parts provided by DISA/DEPS such as Quest web parts, content sliders, accordions, etc...
- Developed junior staff to perform as a SharePoint SCA.
- Extended the functionality of SharePoint out-of-the-box forms using HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS.
- Migrated/configured the CIO/G-6 SharePoint portal from SharePoint 2010 to SharePoint 2013.

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc.

12/2014 - 2/2015

Herndon, VA

- Surge support for Air Force Civil Engineer Portal functioning as a front end developer.
- Provided input on the creation of site content types.
- Custom development of SharePoint out-of-the-box forms using JavaScript, jQuery, and HTML.

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc. 8/2013 – 12/2014

Washington, DC

- SharePoint/Project Server Site Collection Administrator supporting the EPA Office of the CFO Program Management Office
- Created document libraries, pages, workflows, site templates
- Created/managed data views
- Created custom groups and permissions
- Created reports using Excel Services

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc.

3/2000 - 7/2013

- PowerBuilder developer supporting the EPA Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Information System (CERCLIS)
- Maintained existing code and developed new features for CERCLIS and its administration support application, Sysadmin.
- Wrote the application design document during the CERCLIS single database conversion. The document detailed the application changes being made to the CERCLIS application as the back end was consolidated from 11 separate databases into one.
- Provided support to team software documentation deliverables to include authoring Application Design
 Documents for each release, as well as providing review of Requirement Documents for application changes and
 Test Scripts for 3rd party testers.
- Worked with Oracle DBAs to create/modify PL/SQL procedures, creation of new database tables.

Litton PRC, Systems Analyst

5/1996 - 2/2000

- PowerBuilder developer supporting U.S. Army Personnel Command
- Supported development of Department of the Army Photo Management Information System (DAPMIS),
 Officer Selection Support System (OSSS), & Total Officer Personnel Management Information System II (TOPMIS II).

Virginia Army National Guard, Supply Specialist/Unit Armorer

9/1987 - 9/1996

EDUCATION

George Washington University – Full Stack Developer Boot Camp (expected: April 2019) Strayer College Diploma, Computer Information Systems 1995 BS Political Science, James Madison University, 1992